{"tossups": [{"question": "During this battle, the Knyphausen Detachment failed to mount a counterattack due to malfunctioning guns. The call sign \u201cVictory or Death\u201d was used for one side in this battle which benefited from Johann Rall\u2019s reluctance to send out a patrol in bad weather. Followed shortly by an engagement at Princeton, this battle was made possible by one side\u2019s nighttime crossing of the Delaware River. For ten points, name this Christmas Day battle in which the Hessians were surprised by George Washington.", "answer": "Battle of<em><b> Trenton</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The Madden Committee investigated this event for which Roman Rudenko claimed the Germans should be held responsible. Zbigniew [ZBIG-nyef] Brzezinski visited a memorial to the victims of this event at the invitation of Mikhail Gorbachev. The crimes from this event also occurred at Kalinin and Kharkiv prisons. Resulting in over 22,000 deaths, this event was conducted by the NKVD in 1940. For ten points, name this mass execution of Polish officers by the Red Army during World War Two.", "answer": "<em><b> Katyn</b></em> Massacre", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "As chair of the Second Bretton Woods Conference, this man proposed an International Clearing Union. This man was opposed by the \u201cHeavenly Twins\u201d at the Paris Peace Conference. This economist\u2019s argument for deficit spending was the inspiration for Franklin D. Roosevelt\u2019s New Deal policies. For ten points, name this economist who argued against the Treaty of Versailles in The Economic Consequences of the Peace.", "answer": "John Maynard<em><b> Keynes</b></em>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Economics"}, {"question": "In the trial resulting from this event, Max Steuer discredited a testimony that was repeated numerous times by Kate Alterman, helping to eventually acquit Max Blanck and Isaac Harris. People like Josephine Goldmark and Rose Schneiderman used this event to campaign for better working conditions. For ten points, name this 1911 disaster that saw the death of 146 workers in the Asch building of a namesake New York City garment factory.", "answer": "<em><b> Triangle Shirtwaist</b></em> Factory Fire", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This city is the birthplace of Juliette Gordon Low, John C. Fremont and songwriter Johnny Mercer. This city\u2019s First African Baptist Church began meeting in 1773 and claims to be the first black Baptist congregation in North America. The oldest standing rail facility in the U.S. is located in this city that also hosted the 1996 Olympic sailing competition. For ten points, name this city found on the Yamacraw Bluff, on the site of the 1733 landing of James Oglethorpe, the original colonial capital of Georgia.", "answer": "<em><b> Savannah</b></em>, Georgia", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The flag of this city features a mine shaft and furnace, representing its place as the mining capital of the Russian empire. This city was founded by Vasily Tatischev and Georg Wilhelm de Gennin as an iron plant in 1723. This city, named for the wife of the Tsar at the time of its founding, is home to the Church of the Blood on the former site of the Ipatiev House. For ten points, name this second-largest Siberian city, formerly known as Sverdlosk, where the Romanov family was executed.", "answer": "<em><b> Yekaterinburg</b></em> (accept<em><b> Sverdlosk</b></em> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "One section of this book claims that philosophy was only possible as a result of the development of leisure and that \u201cvain and erroneous\u201d Greeks had aided the forces of darkness. This book\u2019s frontispiece depicts the title figure made up of several smaller men. This book claims that before the establishment of its title figure, life was \u201csolitary, poor, nasty, brutish, and short.\u201d For ten points, name this book of political philosophy by Thomas Hobbes which advocates for an absolute monarchy.", "answer": "<em><b> Leviathan</b></em> or The Matter, Forme and Power of a Common-Wealth Ecclesiasticall and Civil", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "This man took one post after the death of Frank Knox, often arguing with colleague Henry Stimson over deployment of supplies to the Pacific. This man left a note citing Ajax by Sophocles shortly before committing suicide by jumping out of a window. After the passing of the National Security Act of 1947, the posts of Secretary of the Army, Navy, and Air Force were merged into a single position that this man became the first to assume. For ten points, name this first US Secretary of Defense.", "answer": "James<em><b> Forrestal</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "Most of the victims of this event were killed in a location whose name was inspired by a Jacques Offenbach operetta, during a performance by the band Eagles of Death Metal. Retaliation for an airstrike known as Operation Chammal was cited as the motive for this event whose target locations included the Bataclan theater. Saleh Abdeslam fled to Brussels after this event which was declared an act of war by Francois Hollande. 137 people were killed in, for ten points, what series of attacks in 2015?", "answer": "November 2015<em><b> Paris</b></em> Attacks (accept any answers that indicate the violence in<em><b> Paris</b></em>, accept <em><b>Bataclan</b></em> before mentioned)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "During this event, a friendly contest was proposed to determine which country had the best cheese. Attendants to this event included Viscount Castlereagh and the Prince of Talleyrand. Klemens von Metternich led this event, which was completed after a decisive victory for the Duke of Wellington. For ten points, name this 1814-15 meeting between the powers of Europe to decide how to maintain the balance of power after Napoleon\u2019s defeat.", "answer": "<em><b> Congress</b></em> of<em><b> Vienna</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This eldest son of Julia Domna is depicted next to his brother, whose face is blotted out, in one of the only paintings to survive from the Roman Era. This ruler, who sacked Alexandria after its inhabitants satirized him for killing his brother, was succeeded by Macrinus. This ruler\u2019s constitution extended citizenship to all residents of the empire. For ten points, name this son of Septimius Severus, a Roman emperor who constructed monumental baths whose ruins still stand in Rome.", "answer": "<em><b> Caracalla</b></em> (accept Marcus Aurelius<em><b> Antoninus</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This man was injured at the Battle of Kunersdorf during the Seven Years\u2019 War. A parade in honor of this man is held every September in New York City. A text called the \u201cBlue Book\u201d translated the teachings of this man into English for the men whom he instructed. That book by this man taught troops how to use bayonets, based on his experience as an officer for Frederick the Great. For ten points, name this Prussian military instructor who drilled the Continental Army at Valley Forge.", "answer": "Baron Friedrich Wilhelm von<em><b> Steuben</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "Orphans in this country were benefited in 1990 when the wives of the Beatles organized the Nobody\u2019s Child charity album. The decretei are a generation of this country\u2019s children born in the wake of Decree 770. The authors of Freakonomics noted the correlation between this country\u2019s baby boom-related economic downturn and the violent overthrow of this country\u2019s dictator on Christmas, 1989. For ten points, name this country once led by Nicolae Ceausescu [chow-SHESS-koo].", "answer": "<em><b> Romania</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Andrei Zhdanov commissioned this composer to create a Suite on Finnish Themes that was intended to be played in Helsinki at the conclusion of the Winter War. The encroaching Wehrmacht was thought to be the inspiration of the \u201cinvasion theme\u201d of one work by this composer dedicated to a city that withstood a nearly 900 day siege during World War Two. For ten points, name this Russian composer of the \u201cLeningrad\u201d Symphony.", "answer": "Dmitri<em><b> Shostakovich</b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "This monarch caused controversy, after working with the priest Le Bel to inspect letters for disloyalty, by ordering the execution of Gian Monaldeschi while staying at Louis XIV\u2019s Fontainbleau palace. A regency headed by Axel Oxenstierna ruled during the early years of this monarch, who chose to abdicate and live in Rome after converting to Catholicism. For ten points, name this queen of the house of Vasa and daughter of Gustavus Adolphus of Sweden.", "answer": "<em><b> Christina</b></em>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "During an 1862 battle occurring around and named for this city, George McClellan attacked John Magruder\u2019s Warwick Line. In another battle at this city, the forces of Thomas Dundas were trapped at Gloucester. That battle in this city ended with negotiations at Moore House and a surrender accepted by Benjamin Lincoln. The Comte de Grasse brought a French fleet to that battle in this city. For ten points, name this Virginia city where the last major battle of the Revolutionary War was fought.", "answer": "<em><b> Yorktown</b></em>, Virginia", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>The Clifford-Elsey Report translated the findings of a work by this man to concrete policy recommendations. This man\u2019s \u201cAmerican Life\u201d was depicted in a 2011 biography by John Lewis Gaddis. The NSC-68 ignored the (+) diplomatic options this man proposed in favor of military action. An article published by this man in Foreign Affairs under the pseudonym \u201cMr. X\u201d portrayed one country as at perpetual war with capitalism and is titled (*) </b> The Sources of Soviet Conduct. For ten points, name this member of the three \u201cWise Men\u201d whose\u201cLong Telegram\u201d formulated the policy of containment.", "answer": "George F(rost)<em><b> Kennan</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>This ruler faced early trouble from two Eberhards, of Bavaria and Franconia, and his half-brother, Thankmar, during his early reign. Berengar of Ivrea submitted to this man who married Berengar\u2019s former prisoner, (+) Adelaide of Italy. Liudolf, this man\u2019s son, died during a rebellious invasion of Italy, and Pope John XII crowned this man before being deposed by this ruler. After defeating the invading (*)</b> Magyars on the Lech, this king of Germany and Italy was crowned Emperor in 962 and thus became Holy Roman Emperor until his 973 death. For ten points, name this man who consolidated the German Reich.", "answer": "<em><b> Otto I</b></em> (accept<em><b> Otto</b></em> the<em><b> Great</b></em>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>In an open letter, this artist offered to sleep with Richard Nixon if he ended the Vietnam War, and that letter by this artist inspired the title of a postponed 2020 Hirshhorn exhibit, One With Eternity. In 1966, this artist commented on (+) Asian-American stereotypes by walking around New York in a kimono before stopping to cry and then promptly walking away as part of her Walking Piece. A series of installations by this artist uses hanging, lighted balls and mirrors to create a sense of never-ending space. The (*)</b> Infinity Room series is by, for ten points, what Japanese artist known for her use of polka dots?", "answer": "Yayoi<em><b> Kusama</b></em>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>An advisor from this kingdom, Constantine Phaulkon, oversaw the murder of several British people in the Mergui massacre. Louis XVI entered an alliance with this kingdom\u2019s monarch, Narai. This kingdom defeated the Taungoo dynasty after King (+) Naresuan defeated Prince Mingyi Swa in an elephant duel. This kingdom\u2019s last dynasty, the Ban Phlu Luang, was defeated by the Konbaung Dynasty in the Second (*) </b> Burmese-Siamese War and was succeeded by the short-lived Thonburi Kingdom under Taksin the Great. For ten points, name this kingdom that ruled Siam from 1351 to 1767.", "answer": "<em><b> Ayutthaya</b></em> Kingdom", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A work by this author helped the popularity of the future king Charles I as it was the first public masque in which the Prince of Wales performed. This man contributed two poems to the opening of the (+) First Folio, including \u201cTo the Memory of My Beloved.\u201dThough this man had a complicated relationship with William Shakespeare, the King\u2019s Men performed this man\u2019s work with Shakespeare himself appearing in (*)</b> Every Man in His Humour. For ten points, name this Elizabethan playwright who popularized the \u201ccomedy of humours\u201d in works such as Volpone and The Alchemist.", "answer": "Ben(jamin)<em><b> Jonson</b></em>", "metadata": "Literature - British Literature - Drama"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man built the Ames Hydroelectric plant to power the Gold King Mine, and he founded the Duquesne Mining Company in Arizona\u2019s Patagonia Mountains. At age 21, this man invented a \u201ccar replacer\u201d and a reversible frog. The (+) Union Switch and Signal Company was founded by this man who witnessed brakemen unable to stop two colliding trains, leading him to create a failsafe compressed air break. This man used (*) </b>AC transformers to compete against Thomas Edison\u2019s DC power in the \u201cWar of the Currents.\u201d For ten points, name this American pioneer in the electrical industry.", "answer": "George<em><b> Westinghouse</b></em>, Jr.", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>A man with this surname was killed atop his horse \u201cFire-Eater\u201d when a bullet struck an artery in his leg at The Peach Orchard. Another man with this surname was controversially replaced by John Bell Hood during the battle of (+) Atlanta. That general with this surname was earlier wounded at the battle of Seven Pines, allowing Robert E. Lee to take command for the first time. The most famous general with this surname was slain attacking Grant\u2019s troops on the first day of the Battle of (*) </b> Shiloh. For ten points, give the surname of Confederate commanders Joseph Eggleston and Albert Sidney.", "answer": "<em><b> Johnston</b></em> (accept Albert Sidney<em><b> Johnston</b></em> until \u201cJohn Bell Hood\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>While at Yale, this man was part of a team with future Citigroup president James Rockefeller, winning gold in rowing at the 1924 Olympics. This man favored male circumcision to avoid cervical cancer and supported placing (+) infants on their abdomen, possibly increasing the risk of SIDS. A work by this man features a chapter on \u201cThe One-Year Old\u201d and supports treating children as (*)</b> individuals, with \u201cNatural loving care.\u201d Offering advice to mothers such as, \u201cYou know more than you think you do\u201d, for ten points, name this pediatrician who wrote the controversial Baby and Child Care.", "answer": "Dr. Benjamin<em><b> Spock</b></em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}